<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>From novice to programmer</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 03:38:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>.Dotfiles</title><description>&lt;p&gt;If you're a developer or just a techie all the specialized shortcuts and installed packages you have are very important to your flow and productivity and if you heaven forbid happen to lose your computer it would be extremely hard to reproduce everything you had, or if you are using multiple computers consistency between machines is key. With this tutorial you will be able to save and retrieve those precious files with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets start by checking out all of the dotfiles &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your terminal and navigate to your root directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;ls-a&lt;/code&gt; and it will give you all the files even the hidden ones which we are looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take note of all the ones you would like to save i.e. vim, bash, gitignore and any others there you would like to save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a directory with in root name .dotfiles &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;mkdir .dotfiles&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then we can start to move your files into that directory ( you can either keep the files as dots or you can change them to something viewable &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;mv .vimrc .dotfiles/vimrc&lt;/code&gt; etc for all the files and folder you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When all files are transferred we will symlink all the files back to where they came from. Go to the .dotfile directory and run this for every file &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ln -s vimrc ~/.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now that we have everything symlinked all that is left is to get them saved on github &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what ever the situation all you need to do is pull the repo and symlink everything back and you will be back  to peak productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/-dotfiles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5826f106-9d61-4505-8410-8bb726098693</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 17:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinner Dash 3</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I was very surprised this break that everyone was so productive and stayed on track. We finished Dinner Dash and i believe we have a solid project, everything seemed to fall into place where we were able to finish strong. Our instructor really didn't get the joke of the theme we choose but oh well we thought it was funny. Although we just finished our first full rails site I cant wait for the next module, we will be moving on to the pivot where we will solidify our knowledge and be able to integrate all the things we've been learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/dinner-dash-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">84254df1-0c37-4278-bc88-397d9ba6ca3c</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 02:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinner Dash 2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;So this week is a short one due to thanksgiving. We have made a lot of progress and seem to be on track to make the deadline. This week we implemented the cart(which might be working) and worked on javascript. As of now we haven't used any javascript and i don't foresee us using any at this time. I look forward to see what gets done the weekend, but for me i'm not flying home for the holiday so it seems like its going to be a productive weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/dinner-dash-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6dfc0abc-e7f8-4b7f-ac66-267915a72d50</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinner Dash</title><description>&lt;p&gt;So this week we started dinner dash the project is going to be the lastest yet, three whole weeks with the same four people. In dinner dash we will be building a restaurant that has a checkout process, cms and secure admin dashboard. We decide on Crossroads Lodge a very cliche mountain lodge serving wild game like bison, bear and mountain lion. This week we mainly concentrated on authorization and authentication, with pushing logic down the stack. My group seems to work really well with each other and have fallen into quite a good workflow. But I hope everything will continue with this efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/dinner-dash-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b76d0e65-0898-4858-b9a8-302d930108c4</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 01:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Contact Manager</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This week we had our mid-module assessments on Sinatra and I was worried I wasn't going to pass but honestly, I did pretty well and busted out a passing score! The rest of the week was different from most because we had a lot of class time and a week long tutorial that was so messed up that most of us had to hack our way through the second half. I thought it was a strange week with all the class time and thought there was no way I could absorb all the knowledge that was given but I know I learned so much. All the instructors were very patient and understanding with all of my questions this week and even when I thought I couldn't learn anymore they embedded so much more in me that I seriously think I can handle whatever is thrown at me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/contact-manager/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">83c1eb41-df1e-43c8-b064-c9ef1aa579b6</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 04:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Clone Wars</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This week started with us learning about using SQL and Sequel and how use it to provide data dynamically to our sites. We moved from there to learn about basic authentication to protect our sites. We were assigned Clone Wars a 2 week project to copy the front end from a local restaurant and create a fully operational back end to supply all the data needed to create, edit and delete data from the database and provide it to the site. This week we finished with all of the front end and created the back end with sqlite3 and then hosted the site on Heroku. Throughout the project when we went to push to Heroku and found out that Heroku only supports posgreSQL. I was very thankful for this because what we originally used was very generic and could be used on both. This has been really interesting project! With having to endure two weeks and three people, its a lot different than I was expecting but my group seems to work really well together and have all been very productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2014/12/Screen-Shot-2014-12-08-at-6-57-40-PM.png" alt="LoDo Jimmys"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/clone-wars/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f652ec54-c19c-4066-b0c1-9ffe1c1b87d8</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 17:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>IdeaBox</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2014/12/Screen-Shot-2014-12-08-at-4-18-55-PM.png" alt="Turing-Bistro"&gt;
The start of this new module is awesome. We get to actually see what we create. This week started off with making a small site for the Turing Bistro and I thought it was tons of fun. I had used html and css before so this was just a refresher and had nothing to do with Ruby. When the time came we did our first Sinatra app IdeaBox it was a great way to do web design and integrate Ruby to create a very cool project that you can enter an idea and it then turns around and stores it and lists them dynamically and be ranked. It was a nice intro and now we move into the realm of full blown websites.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/ideabox/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">96c42984-a933-47cf-9c5f-91548e1b79ad</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blogging with Ghost and Github pages</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to under go the feat of creating a blog with my exploits at Turing. I initially decide to do blogger since I already had a Google account, but after a short amount of time I realized that it was not going to allow me to do as much as would like to. So I did some research and found Ghost, a very nice and easy to use blogging service that had all the add-ons and custom themes I could ever want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the Ghost platform but I did not like the fact that I had to pay $10 a month to run a blog. When people call me a geek I say, “Thank you!” I took away from this and looked for free hosting and blogging platforms. I found that Ghost could be hosted on a server, be it local or web, and went on to looking for a way to host it on github pages. I found two blogs that explained how the process went but neither of them were what I was needing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In prefacing the instructions, I should tell you that I am running a mac so depending on what rig you're using, it might be slightly different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start by downloading the enviroments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Node &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/dist/v0.10.33/node-v0.10.33.pkg" title="Node"&gt;Download Node&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Python &lt;br&gt;
If you have have homebrew run &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;brew install python&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br&gt;
or &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/downloads/release/python-278/" title="Python"&gt;Download Python 2.7.8&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use pip to install buster &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;pip install buster&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And lastly, use wget which is required by buster with &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;brew install wget&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay so now that we have everything installed that we need to run the blog lets get the fun part started.&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the ghost platform to run locally.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a directory that all blog will live in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/zip/ghost-0.5.6.zip" title="Ghost"&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unzip and go to the directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again in your terminal run to install the server &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And then to run the server locally run &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;npm start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/"&gt;http://localhost:2368/&lt;/a&gt; to see that everything is working correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So now that we have the blog running locally, we will get it set up on github with buster.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now to create a Github page for your blog&lt;/strong&gt;         &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to you github profile and create a public repo with the name of your account(for me is the repo name was &lt;strong&gt;larsonkonr.github.io&lt;/strong&gt;) but it you really want to i created a seperate account with the name of what i wanted the blog to be.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the same directory that you put the ghost files setup the location for the static files with &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;buster setup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and when promted enter the repo you just created for me that is &lt;a href="https://github.com/larsonkonr/larsonkonr.github.io.git"&gt;https://github.com/larsonkonr/larsonkonr.github.io.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once that is completed run this to generate the static files &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;buster generate --domain=http://127.0.0.1:2368&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;then cd into static &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;cd static&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now to get it up on github &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git commit -m 'Initial commit'&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All we have to do now is wait! Although github says that you'll only have to wait 10 minutes, I should warn you that I had to wait 26 minutes. After everything it was seriously the hardest wait with constantly clicking refresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change any of the styling you have to edit them in the ghost directory. Boot up your local server and add or change any post you would like. To get that on your hosted blog you need to run &lt;code&gt;buster generate --domain=http://127.0.0.1:2368&lt;/code&gt;  and then add, commit, and push to github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it! Your own blog using ghost hosted on github.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/blogging-with-ghost-and-github-pages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b1d8fee6-e789-4785-902d-22a18f0e2988</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sales Engine 2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This was the final week of my first module and I past my first assessment (WooHoo!) It has been a crazy six weeks and I have learned so much but I know that the future has so much more knowledge for me to learn and I cannot wait. This week we conquered the business intelligence part of sales engine and boy, it was something I wasn't expecting. There was so much data to work with that included having to pull parts from multiple databases and respond with properly formatted data. My partner in sales engine did not pass her assessment and so I had to work on the project by myself while she studied for the retest. It was definitely the hardest thing I have done yet but the knowledge I acquired doing it myself was insurmountable. I'm really looking forward to a week away from school to recuperate and study to be ahead of the game. To be honest, I really cannot wait until I get to dive in to the next module because I hear it is all about the web side of development with Sinatra and Rail. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/sales-engine-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ec42f42c-2370-4f1f-b4f0-0fb958eb31b7</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 18:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sales Engine</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Holey moley they were right about this project being extremely intense and definitely the hardest thing yet! Sales Engine, so far, has been a lot of trial and error to see what will work and produce the right information because this is really the first project to not have any interface in which we interact with. So far, its going really well and we are making good progress with the program. While we're done with all of the parsing of the data to something Ruby can use and basic relationships, now is the hard part, because this weekend we will start the Business Intelligence which is so much harder than the parsing. In Business Intelligence we have to take the data from the parser and create a relationship network to pull the data from multiple locations to provide the asked for information. While I know it will not be easy, I am definitely up for this next challenge!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/sales-engine/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7e04bbd7-18d9-4cd3-a097-50f7631c7507</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 00:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Event Reporter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This week was definitely the hardest so far. We got the project Event Reporter which is a pairing project. It was weird to work with someone on the same project since we hadn't done it yet but it was very successful. It was a dynamic that was interesting to be able to split things up so we both had things to work on on our own. I foudn it a little hard to not do something someone else was working on or change something that they really need but luckily early on we found out about Waffle.io which is a very useful web app to help manage to-dos and to be able to assign people to specific things. Although this week was hard, I've been told that its definitely nothing to be compared to the Sales Engine that we will get on Monday. This will be 2 weeks working with the same person.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/event-reporter/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd7c53e-05a3-49fb-b4aa-5ea139d9afce</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 17:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mastermind</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2014/12/Screen-Shot-2014-11-29-at-3-56-39-PM.png" alt="Mastermind"&gt;
    This week was great. We had quite a bit of new things we learned with testing and REPLs which culminated with us completing the mastermind project. We built a command line version of the code breaking game. I loved this week! It was difficult but we actually had things we could see and show people what we have been learning. I had so much fun working on this project because it was the culmination of the knowledge we have acquired in the last 3 weeks and because there were things we could do to our projects to make them our own. I decided to add so cool ASCII art and colors. I also tried to insert some nerd jokes here and there. During this week we had our first interaction with pairing which I enjoed because it was a way we could fix some of our problems with another set of eyes. I'm looking forward to next week because people mentioned that it was going to be very hard but I really want to tackle this next project head on and really see what I have learned so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/mastermind/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">93d751b9-f9ed-4630-a9fc-05923a80bc10</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 22:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Enumerables</title><description>&lt;p&gt;So everyone was right last week in saying that this was just the beginning. The knowledge we were given this week to learn was great because with learning enumerables I found it interesting but also very difficult to try to memorize all the enumerables to use to be able to complete the exercises the right way. I realized this week there will be a lot of searching on both the Ruby docs and Google. I'm so thankful for the teachers to be there for help, not only during class time but before school, lunch and after school. Someone told me that Ruby is a great language to be in not only because Ruby developers are in demand but also that the Ruby community very collaborative. While this week was good it was also quite stressful because it was also Denver Startup Week which had events almost every night. I tried to go to as many as possible with my classmates and while I was there I was reassured exactly why this was the right decision for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/enumerables/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f0d08fa6-9940-4739-9175-76077ecc6f5c</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 23:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Intro to Turing</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This week started out with building the furniture for the new classroom we will be occupying, which I had been told was borrowed from Amazon who makes their new employees build their own desks. I thought this was an amazing idea to get us to bond as a group. I had completed some things that they had sent me to prepare me before coming to Turing. One of those was to do Ruby in 100 minutes but they also had us do it as a group which I thought was so excellent because we got an introduction to Ruby before starting and then to reiterate the same infomation and ask questions. We had a group of exercises called mythical creatures assigned to us and it was nice to be able to put some of the things we were learning to work and be able to see the results. They also had arranged a scavenger hunt for us to complete in a group. I had never been to Denver before so it was a great experience to be able to travel around the city looking at all the art and historical locations. We were introduced to GIT for the first time and I think it is a great product I could imagine myself using this for college papers and for business work rather than sending CDs or flash drives around. This is going to be an interesting venture for me with my dyslexia but I have strong support behind me from all of the instructors and mentors. There were so many things being thrown at us this week but by what I have heard this is just the beginning. This week has been amazing and I cannot wait to see what the future has in store.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/intro-to-turing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7b158830-08e6-4c4b-9dc8-e58df8719317</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 21:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>History</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start by giving you a recap of my life. I was born in Iowa and moved around a lot but I always had my family and computers. When I was little my dad worked for many start up companies so I was named the resident cable rat, I would take cords and run them though the crawl spaces. After I would finish my dad would allow me to hang out in the office I always gravitated towards the IT desk watching the gentleman take apart computers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started playing with computers shortly after I would take them apart and put them back together again. I would install a bunch software to modify and change to see how it changed. In high school I took computer programming and engineering classes so I could mess with all the tech. I was amazing. After graduating I attended college but it was not the environment for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved back with my family and got a job as a computer tech. I started with just my basic knowledge but the man I worked for taught me a lot and also taught me some bad things and thats when I decided I wanted to be better then him. So I started my own company with a partner. I met wife during this time. It was great I did all the computer work so there was nothing that went out that I did not personal touch. It was a good feeling that I was helping all these people and providing a service for about half as much as anyone else in town. We were doing great and expanding quickly. I was good at it there was no problem I ran into that I could not fix. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then my partner did some questionable stuff and I gave im an ultimatum he then did it again and so I packed up all my stuff and left. I lost all my money I had invest so I then went to work for Home Depot to support myself, it was fun work I drove forklifts and loved helping customers. I was Team Depot coordinator, I handled all volunteer projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I married the woman of my dreams and we had a beautiful baby boy. I switched jobs to go work for Lowes. But my beautiful wife told me to do what I love and that she would support me with whatever I decided to do. My cousin went through a accelerated software course call Hungry Academy, after that he was doing great. He suggested to me that I should look into attending Turing it was the new iteration of the program he did. They said that they could take someone with no programming experience and turn them into a developer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then applied for the program, they had a intense process that included a resume, video submission, github letter, and lsat questions just to get an interview. I waited impatiently for a response. then received and email scheduling an interview. I was so ecstatic. I did my interview with and instructor from the school which was nerve-racking, I had done interviews but this could change my life then he had me do so lsat problems while he was watching and asking questions. I had no idea how it went but i couldn't wait for a response either way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They contacted me and told me I was accepted. I was a great day and a day that was so hard because I would have to move 4 states away and leave my wife and newborn son while I went to school for 7 months. As the day grew nearer that I would have to left it became harder to think I was leaving my family.I quit my job a week before I left for school to fit in as much family friends and fun. My wife and my sister took me to the airport and had one last meal with me before I flew off.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-from-novice-to-programmer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">26f55fd2-3756-4f3f-997d-25fcdd59c71b</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 21:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>