<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>From novice to programmer</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 20:29:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Sales Engine</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Holey moley they were right about this week being extremely intense and definitely the hardest thing yet! Sales Engine, so far, has been a lot of trial and error to see what will work and produce the right information because this is really the first project to not have any interface in which we interact with. So far, its going really well and we are making good progress with the program. While we're done with all of the parsing of the data to something Ruby can use, now is the hard part, because this weekend we will start the Business Intelligence which is so much harder than the parsing. In Business Intelligence we have to take the data from the parser and create a relationship network to pull the data from multiple locations to provide the asked for information. While I know it will not be easy, I am definitely up for this next challenge!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/sales-engine/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7e04bbd7-18d9-4cd3-a097-50f7631c7507</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 00:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Event Reporter</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This week was definitely the hardest so far. We got the project Event Reporter which is a pairing project. It was weird to work with someone on the same project since we hadn't done it yet but it was very successful. It was a dynamic that was interesting to be able to split things up so we both had things to work on on our own. I foudn it a little hard to not do something someone else was working on or change something that they really need but luckily early on we found out about Waffle.io which is a very useful web app to help manage to-dos and to be able to assign people to specific things. Although this week was hard, I've been told that its definitely nothing to be compared to the Sales Engine that we will get on Monday. This will be 2 weeks working with the same person.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/event-reporter/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd7c53e-05a3-49fb-b4aa-5ea139d9afce</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 17:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mastermind</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2014/12/Screen-Shot-2014-11-29-at-3-56-39-PM.png" alt="Mastermind"&gt;
    This week was great. We had quite a bit of new things we learned with testing and REPLs which culminated with us completing the mastermind project. We built a command line version of the code breaking game. I loved this week! It was difficult but we actually had things we could see and show people what we have been learning. I had so much fun working on this project because it was the culmination of the knowledge we have acquired in the last 3 weeks and because there were things we could do to our projects to make them our own. I decided to add so cool ASCII art and colors. I also tried to insert some nerd jokes here and there. During this week we had our first interaction with pairing which I enjoed because it was a way we could fix some of our problems with another set of eyes. I'm looking forward to next week because people mentioned that it was going to be very hard but I really want to tackle this next project head on and really see what I have learned so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/mastermind/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">93d751b9-f9ed-4630-a9fc-05923a80bc10</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 22:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Enumerables</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;So everyone was right last week in saying that this was just the beginning. The knowledge we were given this week to learn was great because with learning enumerables I found it interesting but also very difficult to try to memorize all the enumerables to use to be able to complete the exercises the right way. I realized this week there will be a lot of searching on both the Ruby docs and Google. I'm so thankful for the teachers to be there for help, not only during class time but before school, lunch and after school. Someone told me that Ruby is a great language to be in not only because Ruby developers are in demand but also that the Ruby community very collaborative. While this week was good it was also quite stressful because it was also Denver Startup Week which had events almost every night. I tried to go to as many as possible with my classmates and while I was there I was reassured exactly why this was the right decision for me.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/enumerables/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f0d08fa6-9940-4739-9175-76077ecc6f5c</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 23:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Intro to Turing</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This week started out with building the furniture for the new classroom we will be occupying, which I had been told was borrowed from Amazon who makes their new employees build their own desks. I thought this was an amazing idea to get us to bond as a group. I had completed some things that they had sent me to prepare me before coming to Turing. One of those was to do Ruby in 100 minutes but they also had us do it as a group which I thought was so excellent because we got an introduction to Ruby before starting and then to reiterate the same infomation and ask questions. We had a group of exercises called mythical creatures assigned to us and it was nice to be able to put some of the things we were learning to work and be able to see the results. They also had arranged a scavenger hunt for us to complete in a group. I had never been to Denver before so it was a great experience to be able to travel around the city looking at all the art and historical locations. We were introduced to GIT for the first time and I think it is a great product I could imagine myself using this for college papers and for business work rather than sending CDs or flash drives around. This is going to be an interesting venture for me with my dyslexia but I have strong support behind me from all of the instructors and mentors. There were so many things being thrown at us this week but by what I have heard this is just the beginning. This week has been amazing and I cannot wait to see what the future has in store.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/intro-to-turing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7b158830-08e6-4c4b-9dc8-e58df8719317</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 21:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>History</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Let me start by giving you a recap of my life. I was born in Iowa and moved around a lot but I always had my family and computers. When I was little my dad worked for many start up companies so I was named the resident cable rat, I would take cords and run them though the crawl spaces. After I would finish my dad would allow me to hang out in the office I always gravitated towards the IT desk watching the gentleman take apart computers. 

I started playing with computers shortly after I would take them apart and put them back together again. I would install a bunch software to modify and change to see how it changed. In high school I took computer programming and engineering classes so I could mess with all the tech. I was amazing. After graduating I attended college but it was not the environment for me. 

I moved back with my family and got a job as a computer tech. I started with just my basic knowledge but the man I worked for taught me a lot and also taught me some bad things and thats when I decided I wanted to be better then him. So I started my own company with a partner. I met wife during this time. It was great I did all the computer work so there was nothing that went out that I did not personal touch. It was a good feeling that I was helping all these people and providing a service for about half as much as anyone else in town. We were doing great and expanding quickly. I was good at it there was no problem I ran into that I could not fix. 

Then my partner did some questionable stuff and I gave im an ultimatum he then did it again and so I packed up all my stuff and left. I lost all my money I had invest so I then went to work for Home Depot to support myself, it was fun work I drove forklifts and loved helping customers. I was Team Depot coordinator, I handled all volunteer projects. 

I married the woman of my dreams and we had a beautiful baby boy. I switched jobs to go work for Lowes. But my beautiful wife told me to do what I love and that she would support me with whatever I decided to do. My cousin went through a accelerated software course call Hungry Academy, after that he was doing great. He suggested to me that I should look into attending Turing it was the new iteration of the program he did. They said that they could take someone with no programming experience and turn them into a developer. 

I then applied for the program, they had a intense process that included a resume, video submission, github letter, and lsat questions just to get an interview. I waited impatiently for a response. then received and email scheduling an interview. I was so ecstatic. I did my interview with and instructor from the school which was nerve-racking, I had done interviews but this could change my life then he had me do so lsat problems while he was watching and asking questions. I had no idea how it went but i couldn't wait for a response either way. 

They contacted me and told me I was accepted. I was a great day and a day that was so hard because I would have to move 4 states away and leave my wife and newborn son while I went to school for 7 months. As the day grew nearer that I would have to left it became harder to think I was leaving my family.I quit my job a week before I left for school to fit in as much family friends and fun. My wife and my sister took me to the airport and had one last meal with me before I flew off.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-from-novice-to-programmer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">26f55fd2-3756-4f3f-997d-25fcdd59c71b</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 21:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Welcome to From novice to programmer</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello my name is Konr Larson. I am attending Turing school of software and design, specifying in ruby. I had little to no experience before attending Turing. It is going to be difficult but a very rewarding experience. This blog is going to be about me and my experience, and about anything else I find interesting.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-from-novice-to-programmer-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">532d8068-c324-4a33-96d4-1c85bd70a7c1</guid><dc:creator>Konr Larson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 21:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>